Enter.
进来
Hey, Mr. Zhang.
张主任
Ling Dong, what can I do for you?
凌冬 你怎么来了
about the physics competition
您上次跟我说的
you mentioned last time,
那个物理竞赛
I've decided to give it a try.
我决定还是参加一下
Great.
好啊
That's good news.
好事
However, this means
但是这样的话
I won't be able to participate in
才艺比赛那边
the talent competition.
我就参加不了了
I'll have to quit.
我得退赛
You've got to think this over.
这事你得想清楚了
It would be a pity if you dropped out.
你如果放弃了的话可惜了
There's a scheduling conflict,
时间撞了我也是没办法
and I feel the physics competition
我觉得还是物理竞赛
is more important to me.
对我来说比较重要一些
Alright, I got it.
好 我知道了
Let me handle it.
那我来协调
As for you,
你呢
just focus on the physics competition.
踏踏实实准备物理竞赛
Thank you, sir.
谢谢主任
[No problem.]
不客气
Jinghui!
灰哥 灰哥
What's up?
干什么 干什么
Why are you yelling? I'm not dead.
喊什么喊 我没死呢
[Attention, students,]
各位同学
[we have an announcement.]
现在插播一条通知
[Due to personal reasons,]
由于个人原因
[Ling Dong from Class 5 of Grade 11, has]
我校高二五班凌冬同学
[withdrawn from the talent competition.]
退出才艺大赛投票选拔
[The current rankings have changed accordingly,]
目前比赛排名顺延
[with Xiao Xiaohua now in the lead]
排名第二的肖小画同学
[with a high number of votes.]
高票领先
Just...
就
About this...
这个
I've already told you.
早就跟你说了
Don't bother.
不要浪费时间
Whoa, impressive.
看不出来啊
You pulled strings behind the scenes.
你还会暗地里做手脚
That was really unexpected.
真是小瞧你了
Let's get one thing clear, OK?
搞清楚好不好
You were the one pulling strings,
暗地里搞手脚的是你
not me.
不是我
You can't just quit this competition
这个比赛不是你想退出
whenever you want.
就随便退出那么容易的
Where are you off to, Jinghui?
灰哥干嘛去啊
[They say life is like]
都说生活就像
[growing a hyacinth.]
养育一盆风信子
[Not until the last moment,]
不到最后一刻
[you never know]
你永远也不知道
[what color the flower will bloom.]
它会开出什么颜色的花
[Just like you never know]
就像你永远也不知道
[whether the next second will bring you]
下一秒等待你的
[a surprise or a shock.]
是惊喜还是惊吓
Xiaohua,
小画
you're now in the first place.
你现在是第一名了
We're now rivals.
我们是竞争对手了
Good luck, Little Jokester.
加油 小笑话
Ms. Fang, this isn't fair.
方老师 这不公平吧
For such an event like the talent contest,
才艺大赛这么大一个比赛
Ling Dong can't just quit like that.
凌冬他说退出就退出了
Ling Dong has a physics competition
凌冬月底
at the end of the month,
要参加物理竞赛
Mr. Zhang has given special permission.
张主任特批的
Do you have an issue with that?
你有什么问题
Not at all.
没问题
He had an exit plan
参加之前
even before he applied.
就已经想好退路了
That's so low.
太卑鄙了
Do you really think
你真以为
I don't know about the little schemes
你背后搞的那些小动作
you've been doing behind the scenes?
老师不知道啊
I...
我
I think you're looking for tasks to do.
我看你就是闲的
Since you're so free,
既然你这么闲
here's some basic exercises
这是我特别为你准备的
I've prepared especially for you.
基础知识题册
Take it, complete it,
你拿回去把它做了
and submit it to Ling Dong for review.
做完交给凌冬检查
No,
不是
Ms. Fang, this isn't fair.
老师 不带这样的
Xiaohua,
小画
what's the matter?
你怎么了 有事吗
Ms. Fang,
方老师
I want to withdraw from the contest, too.
我也想退出才艺比赛
Why?
理由呢
I just don't want to compete.
我不想参加比赛
Xiaohua,
小画
Ling Dong's withdrawal from the contest
凌冬退出才艺比赛呢
was because he had a legitimate reason.
是因为他有正当的理由
He will participate in a physics contest,
他月底要参加物理比赛
and Mr. Zhang has given him permission.
而且张主任已经特批了
If you want to withdraw
如果你只是因为
simply because
不想参加比赛
you don't want to compete.
就要求退赛
I just can't agree to that,
老师不能同意
and I don't have the authority
而且我也没有这个权利
to approve your withdrawal.
同意你退出比赛啊
But Ms. Fang,
可是方老师
I don't have any talents.
我什么才艺都没有
I...
我
You know,
你啊
I think
要我说呢
you lack confidence.
你就是太缺乏自信了
I believe this is a good opportunity
老师觉得你趁这个机会
for you to train and improve.
锻炼锻炼挺好的呀
But...
可是 方
No 'buts'.
没有可是
Alright, it's almost time for class.
好了 马上要上课了
You should go back.
你们回去吧
Thanks, Ms. Fang.
谢谢方老师
Xiaohua,
小画
just try your best to prepare for it.
你回去好好准备准备
I'm really looking forward to your
老师很期待你在
performance in the talent competition.
才艺比赛上的精彩表演
I believe in you.
我相信你
Good luck!
加油
Go back to class now.
回去上课吧
Go ahead.
去吧
Now let's discuss
下面我们来聊一下
the voting for
关于这次才艺比赛的
this talent competition.
投票活动
Many students from each class
现在各班都还有
haven't voted yet.
很多同学没有投票
I believe it's
我觉得我们学生会
our Student Union's duty
有义务组织好
to organize this contest properly.
这次的评选
Everyone knows
相信大家也知道
that this talent competition
这次的才艺比赛呢
is an opportunity to represent our school,
是要代表我们学校的
so it must be
所以一定要是
the most outstanding student.
最优秀的人
Ling Dong is a suitable choice,
本来凌冬同学是可以的
but unfortunately, he withdrew.
可惜的是他退赛了
Ling Dong withdrew,
凌冬退赛了
but there are other candidates.
有其他人
He's the only option.
又不是非他不可
But now,
可是现在的
among those with high votes,
高票人选当中
there isn't anyone particularly
并没有特别合适的
outstanding to represent our school.
可以代表我们学校的人选
How can there not be?
怎么没有
Mengyu, you're also
梦予 你现在的票数
among the top nominees.
也在前列呀
I'm not good enough.
我现在还不够优秀
You're still better than
那也总比
that Xiaohua, aren't you?
那个肖小画强吧
You're making it hard for me
你这么说我也很为难
but I think the Student Union
不过我觉得我们学生会
should really
确实应该要起到
set a good example.
模范带头作用
Then it should definitely be you.
那更应该是你了
Mengyu has competed before
梦予之前就参加过比赛
and has experience.
很有经验
Plus,
而且
she's the president of our Student Union.
又是咱们学生会的主席
It's her responsibility.
当仁不让啊
Mengyu, at this point,
梦予 都这个时候了
we don't need modesty.
你可千万不能谦虚
After all, participating in the contest
毕竟才艺比赛
is about representing our school.
要代表的是我们学校
It's not a trivial matter.
可不是儿戏
Alright then.
那好吧
But just to be clear,
不过事先说好
I'm not trying to hog the limelight.
我可不是要抢这个风头
It's just that we
只是确实要有一个
genuinely need someone
这么样的人选
to represent our school.
代表我们学校
Then I will certainly try my best
那我一定会好好努力
to be a role model for everyone.
给大家做一个表率作用
After the meeting,
那大家等散会之后
please help
麻烦发动一下
encourage your classmates to vote.
身边的同学投票
It's for the benefit
毕竟这也是
of our school, after all.
为了我们学校好
OK.
没问题
That'll be all.
散会
Ma Yiming,
马一鸣同学
Mengyu.
梦姐
The photo on the flyer
之前那个
was a bit unflattering.
宣传单上的照片有点丑
Sorry, Mengyu,
不好意思 梦姐
I didn't realize you disliked it.
我不知道你不喜欢
And about that ribbon,
还有上次那个绶带
my name was printed too small.
我的名字有点小
I won't do it again, I promise.
我不搞了 绝对不搞了
Oh, that's not what I meant.
哎呀 我不是这个意思
Mengyu, you don't have to explain.
梦姐 你不用说了
I heard everything.
我刚才都听见了
You're working too hard for the contest.
你参加比赛太辛苦了
I should have given it more thought.
是我没有考虑周全
Don't worry.
你放心
I definitely won't
我以后绝对不会
pull tricks like that anymore.
再干这种事了
Who told you to stop?
谁不让你拉了
If you're going to do it, do it right.
你要拉就好好拉
I'll send you a photo of mine later.
回头我发你张照片
Use this one.
用这个
Aye, aye, ma'am, consider it done!
好 保证完成任务
Please,
你好
vote for Xu Mengyu from
请支持高二五班
Class 5, Grade 11!
徐梦予一票
Thanks!
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Please give Xu Mengyu your vote,
请大家给徐梦予同学
thanks a lot!
投上一票 谢谢
Please vote for Xu Mengyu!
请大家支持一下徐梦予
Thanks.
谢谢
Please don't vote for me anymore.
大家千万不要再给我投票
Don't worry, Xiaohua,
放心 小画
I will definitely support you in this.
我一定会支持你
No, that's not what I'm...
不是 我不是这个意
No need to say more.
不用再说
We're classmates.
我们都是同班同学
I will surely have your back.
我肯定会支持你的
Guys, please vote for Xiaohua!
请大家投肖小画一票
Vote for Xiaohua!
支持肖小画
Please, everyone,
请大家千万
don't vote for me!
不要给我投票
Don't vote for Xiao Xiaohua.
大家不要给肖小画投票
I noticed yesterday,
我看昨天
by the end of voting,
截止投票的时候
Mengyu was still in the lead.
好像还是梦予领先
It's definitely going to be Mengyu.
肯定就是梦予了
I feel that way as well.
我也这么觉得
[Now, we will announce,]
下面广播宣布
[after voting]
经过公选投票
[and discussion,]
和校方讨论决定
[the one representing Chenjun High School]
本届辰郡中学代表学校
[in the talent competition will be]
参加才艺大赛的最终得主是
[Xiao Xiaohua]
高二五班
[from Class 5, Grade 11.]
肖小画同学
[She will represent Chenjun High School]
她将代表辰郡中学
[in the final qualification of the citywide]
参加全市中学生
[high school students' talent competition.]
才艺大赛的最终选拔
[Let's extend]
在此对肖小画同学
[warm congratulations to Xiao Xiaohua.]
表示热烈祝贺
Xiaohua, that's awesome!
小画 厉害啊
You've surprised us all!
你真是一匹黑马呀
Xiaohua?
小画
Are you happy?
现在你满意了
We're screwed!
完了 完了 完了
Our school can
咱们学校今年
kiss the award goodbye this year.
肯定别想得奖
Mengyu,
梦予
it'd be better if you had been elected.
要是你当选多好
It's fine.
没事
Liu Shu,
刘姝
What's that supposed to mean?
你说这话什么意思
Just as it sounds.
就字面上的意思呗
Can't you understand?
听不懂啊
Her singing is so off-key,
肖小画唱歌跑调都跑到
she's lost all sense of pitch.
喜马拉雅山上去了
Am I not allowed to
我就是对这个结果
question the result?
表示质疑不行吗
But everyone is willing
可是大家就愿意
to vote for her,
给她投票
to choose her.
就愿意选她
Are you jealous?
你忌妒啊
I think
我看
everyone just wants to see a joke.
大家是想看笑话吧
No wonder they call her Little Jokester.
怪不得都叫她小笑话呢
Liu Shu,
我说刘姝啊
I have a question for you.
我问你个问题
Why do you
你为什么要管她
call her Little Jokester?
叫小笑话
Why can't she
她怎么就
participate in the talent competition?
不能去参加才艺大赛呢
This is about representing the school.
才艺大赛代表的是学校
Is she capable of doing that?
肖小画她能代表得了吗
She's definitely capable
我说她能
because I say so!
她就是能
Congratulations, Xiaohua.
恭喜你啊 小画
It seems that the task
看来这次
to represent our school
替校出征的任务
has been entrusted to you this time.
就交到你手里了
You must give it your all,
你可一定要加油
and not to bring shame to our school.
可千万别给学校丢脸啊
Xu Mengyu represented our school last year
去年代表我们学校
in the competition.
参赛的是徐梦予
This year, it's the Little Jokester.
今年竟然是小笑话
The contrast is a bit too harsh, isn't it?
这对比也太惨烈了点吧
I think Xiaohua is quite good.
我觉得肖小画挺好的呀
I'm very optimistic about her.
我很看好她反正
Maybe she can pull off a surprise victory.
说不定还能出奇制胜呢
A surprise victory?
还出奇制胜呢
Cut it out!
别瞎吹了
With her singing skills,
她唱歌那么难听
[our school]
咱们学校
[is likely to end up at the bottom.]
这回估计要垫底了
[So annoying.]
烦死了
[I voted for her just for fun.]
我当时就是随便选的
[How did I know she'd get elected?]
我哪知道她真能选上啊
[Now we're in for a spectacle.]
这下可有的看了
[So annoying.]
好烦啊
[How could this be?]
怎么这样啊
What are you doing,
你要干什么
Xiao Xiaohua?
肖小画
Ling Dong?
凌冬
Do you really want to jump?
你真的想跳下去吗
I...
我
Setbacks are just experiences in life,
挫折只是人生的体验
not the entirety of life.
不是人生的全部
Is it worth sacrificing your life
值得你牺牲生命
just to escape?
去逃避吗
I didn't...
我 我 我没有
Do you know how many people
你知不知道有多少人
struggle to stay alive?
想活着都活不了啊
Do you realize
你知不知道
the life you're giving up so easily is
你现在轻言放弃的生命
something many people can't even hope for?
是多少人奢求不到的
Do you know?
你知不知道
Just one jump, and in an instant,
只要你跳下去 一瞬间
all the people you know,
所有你认识的人
the things you love,
你热爱的东西
will turn to nothing.
都会化为泡影
They will all become meaningless.
都就没有意义了
If you really jumped,
如果你真的跳下去了
you might really
你可能就真的
become a joke, you know?
成为笑话了 你知道吗
Ling Dong!
凌冬
what right do you have to call her a joke?
你凭什么说她是笑话
If you hadn't withdrawn,
如果你不退赛
would she be like this?
她会这样吗
Aren't you aware of the
我为什么会退出
reason of my withdrawal?
你自己心里不清楚吗
Don't you think this
你不要以为这件事
has nothing to do with you.
跟你没有一点关系
Instead of tangling with me here,
与其在这儿跟我纠缠
you'd be better off thinking about
还不如好好想想
how to resolve the situation.
怎么把事解决
You coward!
你个懦夫
Ling Dong, I'm telling you..,
凌冬 我告诉你
Lan Jinghui, you've got it wrong.
兰靖灰 你误会了
Ling Dong just wanted to help me.
凌冬只是想帮我
You don't need to defend him.
你不用替他说话
Every word that came out of his...
他说的每一个字
He didn't...
他没有
This whole thing,
整个事情
I'll shoulder it with you, OK?
我来陪你一块扛 好吗
The world is round.
地球是圆的
If you keep running away like this,
如果你这样一直逃的话
you'll end up back where you started,
你迟早会回到这个原点
right?
不是吗
So instead of...
那与其
What are you two doing?
你们干什么呀
One thought I was about to kill myself,
一个以为我要自杀
and the other lectured me out of the blue.
一个一上来就讲大道理
I just came up here to
我上来我就是想
cry by myself for a bit.
一个人哭一会儿
Alright,
好了 好了 好了
don't cry, don't cry.
不哭 不哭 不哭
Then you should have said that earlier.
那你早说啊
If it's about crying,
那如果是哭的话
I can join you.
我可以陪你一块哭
Is that OK?
对不对
If you need to let it all out,
如果你是要发泄的话
you should shout it out.
那你得喊出来
How?
怎么喊
Come here.
你过来
I'll shout, and you just repeat after me.
我喊一句你喊一句
I'm not Little Jokester!
我不是小笑话
I'm Xiao Xiaohua!
我是肖小画
Louder!
大点声
I'm not Little Jokester.
我不是小笑话
I'm Xiao Xiaohua.
我是肖小画
Put some emotion in.
带点感情
Shout it out with conviction!
掷地有声地喊
I'm not Little Jokester!
我不是小笑话
I'm Xiao Xiaohua!
我是肖小画
That's much better.
这样就好多了
You need to tell them,
你要告诉他们
I, Xiao Xiaohua, can do it!
我肖小画一定可以的
I am THE KING OF THE SCHOOL!
我就是校园冠军
Louder!
大点声
Who's there?
谁啊
Who was shouting on the rooftop?
谁在天台嚷嚷呢
It's dangerous, come down now!
多危险啊 赶紧下来
Run, run, run!
快跑 快跑 快跑
Don't worry, Mr. Zhang won't catch us.
别怕 张主任他追不上
How did you make it this far
我都不知道你这么胆小
with such a fearful nature?
怎么活到现在
No sighing,
不能叹气
happiness will slip away.
幸福会溜走的
But after shouting on the rooftop,
不过你在上面喊了喊
do you feel a lot better?
是不是好多了
But the stage isn't the rooftop.
可是 舞台又不是天台
With so many audiences,
舞台下面那么多观众
what if I get nervous?
我一上台紧张怎么办
You've got me!
不是有我吗
If you nail it, it's your credit.
演得好算你的
If not, it's my fault, alright?
演不好算我的 可以吧
Thank you, Lan Jinghui.
谢谢你 兰靖灰
But what are we going to perform?
但是我们要表演什么呀
Leave it to me.
交给我吧
What?
什么
You want to form a band for her?
你要给肖小画组个乐队
Exactly.
没错
Why?
为什么
Xiaohua is afraid to do it alone,
小画她一个人不敢
so I've decided to do it with her.
所以我决定一起上
No way, Jinghui,
不行 不行 灰哥
I still have trainings.
我得还训练呢
I don't have time.
没有时间呢
If we don't go together,
如果我们要是不上台
she will jump off the rooftop.
肖小画就要上天台了
Are you OK with that?
你忍心吗
I'm going to the rooftop now.
我还是上天台吧
No, apprentice.
不行 徒弟
Don't, Xiaohua!
别 小画
Just for that "don't,"
就冲你这个别字
for your sisterly bond,
姐妹情深
it's decided then. Let's go.
就这么定了 走
Going to perform on stage,
你说这上台表演
without a good pair of shoes,
也没有一双好的鞋子
how am I supposed to do it?
这怎么演
Am I right?
是不是
Just sneakers, right?
不就是球鞋吗
I'll buy them for you.
我给你买
The latest ones!
最新款的
Count me in!
我答应你
Good, that's the spirit!
好 答应痛快
Since you are onboard,
那既然这么痛快
we should...
我们就
Not so fast! I haven't agreed yet!
那我还没答应呢
Tell me your wish.
说出你的愿望
I don't want sneakers.
我不要球鞋
I can't eat them.
球鞋又不能吃
Rehearsals are very draining.
天天排练多消耗呀
I don't know how much I need to eat
都不知道吃多少
to make up for the energy I burn.
才能补回来
It's about food, right?
不就是吃吗
I'll cover your snacks for a month.
我包你一个月零食
Happy now?
满意了吧 可以了吧
A month?
一个月
A quarter.
一个季度
A semester?
一个学期
I want unlimited snacks,
我要一个
all-I-can-eat!
没有期限的零食自由
Here's your "all-I-can-eat."
你要的自由
Meal card?
饭卡
It's yours now, right.
给你 是的
Awesome! All-I-can-eat!
自由万岁
Now that you have your unlimited snacks,
那么自由也有了
and you've got your new sneakers,
球鞋也有了
we'll start rehearsals tomorrow!
明天开始正式排练
Good!
好
Let's go, Xiaohua.
走 小画
Come on, you guys!
快点 快点
On the double, y'all!
快点 快点 快点
Take a look, pick whatever you like.
来 随便看 随便挑
Not bad, Jinghui,
可以啊 灰哥
you're really going all out!
下血本啊
Not really.
没有
My dad used to play music before.
我爸年轻的时候玩音乐的
These are just
这都是家里
a few pieces from home.
随便拿几件过来的
I've been playing since I was little.
所以我从小就玩
I couldn't tell,
看不出来啊
your dad was so swag!
叔叔这么潮呢
But I can't play any of them.
可是我哪一个都不会
When the time comes,
到时候呢
you just stand here,
你就站在这儿
right in the middle,
乐队的C位
as our lead singer.
当我们的主唱
As soon as we start playing,
只要乐队一起范儿
you'll definitely be
你到时候绝对就是
the center of attention.
众星捧月
Relax.
放心啦
Come up, feel it.
上来 感受一下
Come on.
感受
Alright.
来吧
♪Beyond the long pavilion...♪
长亭外
That's enough, stop.
可以了 收一下
Tell me, what seems to be the problem?
你自己说问题是
Cracked.
破音
Correct.
对
Let's lower the pitch
所以我们把音调
just a little bit,
稍微 稍微那么一点
a bit.
放低一点
Again.
再来一遍
♪Beyond the long pavilion, by the ancient road,♪
长亭外 古道边
♪grass dyes green the sky.♪
芳草碧连天
It's slightly better,
比刚刚稍微好了一点
right?
对不对
But the issue is
但是呢 问题是
the breath control, not quite there.
气息 对 不太够
So, the solution is?
那么解决问题方法是
Tell me, Ma Yiming.
马一鸣是什么呢
Panting like a dog.
狗喘气
First, let's practice that.
先练狗喘气
OK, come on.
对 来
Together, OK?
一起啊
Ready?
准备啊
Three, two, one.
三 二 一
Harder.
积极点
You should
具体的呢
practice at home by yourself.
就你回家自己练
Then the second point is,
那么第二点呢
you must project your voice
就是一定要把你的声音
outward.
放出来
Let's start with a vocal warm-up.
那先做一个开声训练吧
It goes like this.
就是
That's the idea, come on.
就这意思 来吧
Make your voice ten times louder,
声音放大十倍
come on, together!
来 一起来
I've marked
我把这谱子上
all the difficult parts
所有有难度的地方
on this for you.
都给你标注出来了
Just follow this for your practice.
你照着练就行
So impressive.
这么厉害
Okey-dokey!
欧了
Just practice.
练吧
[A minus B is a positive number,]
A减B是正数
[so if we use symbols]
那么我们用符号
[to represent it, it means]
表示的话就是说
[A is greater than B, greater than 0.]
A大于B 大于0
Lan Jinghui?
兰靖灰
What are you doing? Listening to music?
你干什么呢 听歌呢
Nah.
没有
My ear hurts.
耳朵疼
I think water got in it
我昨晚洗澡时候
when I was showering last night.
好像进水了
Water got in your ear,
洗澡时候耳朵进水了
and you're still shaking your head?
那你还摇头晃脑的
Won't that make it worse?
你这样不更严重啊
Should I take you to the hospital?
要不要我送你去医院
No, thanks.
不用
Earphones.
耳机
Hand them over.
拿上来
Pay attention.
好好听课
Yes, ma'am.
好的
Alright, let's continue.
好 我们继续啊
[If A...]
如果A
I heard you've been doing well lately.
最近听说你表现不错呀
The teachers have
老师们对你的评价
a high opinion of you.
很高啊
Of course!
那是
Mr. Zhang,
主任
I've been behaving lately.
最近我可是乖乖的
I assure you I haven't caused any trouble.
保证没给您添一点乱
Well, sir,
那主任
if there's nothing else, I'll leave.
没什么事我就先撤了
Not so fast.
等会儿
I was being sarcastic. Can't tell, huh?
你是听不出好赖话是吧
You may leave,
撤可以
but first,
把你那个
show me your notes
学习小组的学习笔记啊
from that study group of yours.
先给我看看
If I find them satisfactory,
我要觉得合格了呢
then you can
你就可以从容地
leave my office.
从我办公室走出去了
Hand them over.
拿来
Sir, can we talk about it?
主任 跟您商量个事呗
You see,
您看
recently, I've been
最近这不是
busy helping classmates
忙着帮着同学们
prepare for the talent competition.
准备节目吗
So, about handing in the notes,
所以这个笔记的事
can we just
咱能不能
delay it a bit?
稍微缓那么一拍
I'll write them later.
我可以之后再写
Let me discuss something with you too.
我也跟你商量点事呗
Please.
您说
About the notes,
笔记的事
you still need to submit now.
你还是得坚持坚持
After all, Lan Jinghui's
毕竟兰靖灰同学的
personal improvement
个人成长呢
is of utmost importance.
是至关重要的
Mr. Zhang,
主任
is it really not OK to improve slower?
慢一点长大真的不行吗
What do you think?
你觉着呢
Hello, Mr. Zhang,
主任好
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
you've dropped your notes.
你的笔记怎么落我这了
I was wondering where they went.
我说怎么找不着了
Mr. Zhang, look,
主任 你看 你看 你看
here they are, right?
在这儿嘛 这不
Well, Mr. Zhang,
那 主任
if there's nothing else, we'll be going.
没事我们就先撤了
See you, sir.
走了 主任
Don't you think that by doing this
别以为这样
I'll be grateful to you.
我就会感激你啊
I'm telling you,
我告诉你
I know you just
我知道你就是
want to see me screw up.
想看我出糗
You don't have good intentions.
没安什么好心
Just go back and make up the notes.
先回去把笔记补了再说
But you've already handed them in.
不是 你不都交了吗
You said it yourself,
你也说了
I don't have good intentions.
我没这么好心
I knew it.
我就知道
Done!
写完了
Peace out!
撤退 拜拜
Wait.
等一下
You've missed too much.
你之前落下的太多了
Make up for those.
把那些补上
Come on, bro, just let me go.
我说大哥 你就放我走吧
Xia Qingtian, Xiao Xiaohua, Ma Yiming are
夏晴天 肖小画 马一鸣
waiting for me to teach them instruments.
还等着我去教他们琴呢
Watch your attitude.
注意自己的态度
Ling Dong,
凌冬
I really didn't expect
真的没有想到
you to become like this.
你现在变成了这个样子
Why didn't I see through
我怎么就没有早一点
your attitude towards me sooner?
看透你对我的态度呢
I really didn't expect
我真的没有想到
you are someone like this.
你是这样的人
You're really cruel!
你真的好狠
So cruel!
好狠
You're so cruel!
你好狠
What's wrong with him?
什么症状
♪Beyond the long pavilion, by the ancient road,♪
长亭外 古道边
♪grass dyes green the sky.♪
芳草碧连天
♪Willows in dusk breeze, fluting fades,♪
晚风拂柳笛声残
♪sun sets behind hills.♪
夕阳山外山
Let's do it again.
再来一遍吧
Mr. Ling, I'm done.
哥哥 我写完了
Good, all correct.
不错 全对了
It's about time.
那时间也差不多了
Let's call it a day.
今天就下课了
Ling Dong, is it over?
小凌同学 下课啦
Right.
对
This is the tutoring fee for this month.
这是你这个月的补课费
Here, take it.
来 拿着
Thank you, auntie.
谢谢阿姨
Xiong has been making
小熊最近补课呀
good progress lately.
进步挺大的
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
No need to thank me.
不用谢我
Auntie, I'll be going then.
阿姨 那我就先走了
Goodbye, Mr. Ling.
凌冬哥哥再见
Goodbye, Xiong.
小熊再见
Son,
冬冬啊
you don't have to do these.
这些事不用你做
Just focus on your studies.
你专心学习就好了
It's OK, mom.
没事 妈
Here, be careful, it's hot.
来 好了 小心烫
Watch out.
当心啊
By the way, Mom,
对了 妈
here's the tutoring fee I've received.
这是我这个月的补课费
We have enough for living expenses.
家里的生活费都够用了
By the way,
对了
I heard there's
二中那边
a good English teacher
听说有一个英语老师
at Second High.
挺不错的
Should I hire her for you?
要不去给你报个名吧
No, mom,
不用了 妈
it's not necessary.
没那个必要
Just keep it.
你就先收着吧
I'm going to study.
我去复习了
The medicine is hot.
药太烫了
Cool it down a bit before taking it, mom.
记得要凉一点再喝啊妈
Don't worry.
放心吧
What's this?
这是
Raw eggs.
生鸡蛋
My dad says
我爸说
eating raw eggs is good for the throat.
喝生鸡蛋对嗓子好
This is our Xia Family's
这可是我们夏家的
secret recipe.
祖传秘方
Can I not eat it?
我能不喝吗
Nope.
不行
How do you feel?
感觉怎么样
Xiaohua, don't throw it all up.
小画 别都吐了呀
It's good for your throat!
保护嗓子
Xiaohua!
小画
Radish!
萝卜
Eating radish clears the airways.
吃萝卜通气
It's perfect for you.
正好适合你
Why would I eat radish?
我唱个歌干吗吃萝卜
You're not getting enough air, right?
你就说你是不是气不通
Here, eat up.
对了 快吃
Stop eating radish.
不要再吃萝卜了
You're not a rabbit.
你又不是兔子
You're not going to make me
你不会又想让我
eat other weird stuff, are you?
吃什么吧
My grandma said
我奶奶说了
eating garlic is especially effective
吃大蒜对有嗓子
for someone whose voices
上不去高音的嗓子
can't hit high notes.
有着特别好的奇效
If you can't handle the raw ones,
如果你吃不惯这个生的
you can eat the pickled ones.
你可以吃这个腊八蒜
It's sweet,
腊八蒜虽然是甜的
and it tastes a bit better,
口感会比它好一点
but it's not as effective as raw ones.
但是效果绝对没有它好
Look, I'm holding it in my mouth.
你看 我含着呢
Very effective.
效果特别好
How's your throat, apprentice?
嗓子还好吧 徒弟
Would you like another piece?
要不再来一块
No!
不要
Please don't make me eat
求你们别再给我吃
anything else.
任何东西了
Stop tormenting me.
别再折磨我了
Or maybe I'll just go on stage
要不我到时候
and recite a poem or something.
随便上台朗诵一首诗
After all, our school
反正学校
doesn't expect me to win anything.
也没指望我拿奖
I think that's a good idea, Jinghui.
我看行 灰哥
Just let me go back to playing basketball.
要不你放我回去打球吧
No.
不行
How can you say
怎么能说这种
something like this?
丧气的话呢
We can't just give up yet.
我们不能轻言放弃
Our fellow students and staff
全校多少师生
are waiting for us to bring glory!
等着我们为校争光呢
Do they even count on us to bring glory?
学校轮得到我们争光吗
Leave that to Ling Dong.
还是留给凌冬吧
Forget about that brat!
凌冬算什么
[Attention all students!]
各位同学请注意
We have an announcement.
现在插播一条最新消息
[Congrats to Ling Dong from]
热烈祝贺我校高二五班
[Class 5, Grade 11 for winning the]
凌冬同学
[first prize in the city physics contest.]
荣获市物理竞赛一等奖
[Chen Luyang won the]
陈璐阳同学荣获
[second prize in the same contest.]
市物理竞赛二等奖
[They have brought honor to our school]
他们为我校争得了荣誉
[and added to its prestige.]
增添了风采
[Let's give these two students]
让我们为这两位同学
[our warmest and]
送上我们最热烈
[most sincere applause.]
最真心的掌声吧
[Bless them.]
祝福他们
Nice work, Ling Dong.
不愧是凌冬
Lan Jinghui, where are you going?
兰靖灰 你要去哪儿
We have found out
已求出
after how many collisions
经过多少次碰撞
the particle's rebound height
颗粒反弹的高度
is less than 0.01 meters.
小于零点零一米
Let's look at the last problem.
咱们来看看最后这道题
Ling...
那个 凌
It's Ling Dong.
凌冬
In our competition class,
咱们竞赛班
you were the only one who solved it.
好像就你做出来了吧
Why don't you
你
tell us all about
先给我们大家讲讲
your thought process.
你的思路
Yeah, yeah.
对啊 对啊
A lot of us
我们好多人
failed to solve the last problem.
都栽在了最后一个大题上
Come on, tell us.
你快给我们讲讲
Ling Dong, share with us.
凌冬 说一下
Come on.
说一下
Just tell us.
快跟我们讲讲
Sir, I also got it right.
老师 我也做出来了
[We now interrupt with breaking news.]
现在插播一条最新消息
[Ling Dong from Class 5, Grade 11]
高二五班的凌冬同学
[will represent Chenjun High School]
将代表辰郡高中
[once again in competition.]
再次出征
[He will be participating]
他将报名参加
[in the city talent competition.]
市才艺大赛的节目选拔
Who's there?
谁啊
Who was shouting on the rooftop?
谁在天台嚷嚷呢
It's dangerous, come down now!
多危险啊 赶紧下来
Who was it?
谁啊
Mr. Zhang,
张主任
regarding the registration
关于物理竞赛
of the physics competition,
报名的事情
I'd like to ask you about the details.
我有些细节想问您一下
OK, we'll talk later.
我知道了 回头再说
Sir,
不是 主任
it might be quite urgent
可能还挺急的
because the competition is close.
因为马上要比赛了
Well, then...
那 那什么
To my office.
去我办公室吧